<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Github | :baopham]]></title>
  <link href="http://baopham.github.io/blog/categories/github/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://baopham.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-08T08:16:57-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://baopham.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bao Pham]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[gbaopham@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[TabRenderer - Quick preview for your tabular data]]></title>
    <link href="http://baopham.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/tabrenderer-quick-preview-for-your-tabular-data/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-14T20:05:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://baopham.github.io/blog/2014/05/14/tabrenderer-quick-preview-for-your-tabular-data</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently learned from a friend that <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/rendering-csv-and-tsv-data">Github renders tabular data</a> (.csv and .tsv) as interactive table, which is really neat. However, it won&rsquo;t work if there&rsquo;s a mismatched column or illegal quoting so I quickly built a <a href="http://tabrenderer.herokuapp.com/">tabrenderer</a> to help people preview their data before pushing them to Github. At first, I was going to use JavaScript to parse the data but was afraid that it will not work the same way as Github&rsquo;s parser. After browsing their repos, I thought it&rsquo;s very likely that they use Ruby to do this given how often they use Ruby for their own projects. <!--more-->Besides, Ruby has its built-in class <a href="http://ruby-doc.org/stdlib-1.9.2/libdoc/csv/rdoc/CSV.html">CSV</a> that takes care of almost everything.</p>

<p>So far, <a href="http://tabrenderer.herokuapp.com/">tabrenderer</a> notifies users of errors that prevent the parser to work such as illegal quoting. It will jump to the row that has such errors but will not scream if there&rsquo;s a mismatched column (it will be obvious to the users though to see some rows don&rsquo;t have columns). The users can either upload their file or simply type the data in the text box.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Euler: Practice Your Math and Programming Skills]]></title>
    <link href="http://baopham.github.io/blog/2012/01/25/project-euler-practice-your-math-and-programming-skills/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://baopham.github.io/blog/2012/01/25/project-euler-practice-your-math-and-programming-skills</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve recently started to participate in this site <a href="http://projecteuler.net/">Project Euler</a>. It&rsquo;s a website with a series of mathematics/programming problems, ranging from easy to very hard. Some problems, if not solved using the right algorithm, can take more than 5 minutes to get the result (personal experience, I forgot that it was running&hellip;). So it only matters if you use correct and efficient algorithms. These problems are meant to be solved in only less than a minute.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Now I&rsquo;m quite addicted to the thrilling feeling of getting the right answer. There are certainly numerous solutions out there on the web (and I admit, sometimes I have to resort to them when I&rsquo;m stuck), but it&rsquo;s always more exciting to try and learn new algorithms and apply them to the problems.</p>

<p>Check out my Git repository of my solutions (mostly in Python because I find it faster and neater to code, no?) to some of the Euler questions: <a href="https://github.com/baopham/projectEuler">baopham/projectEuler</a></p>

<p><img src="http://projecteuler.net/profile/baopham.png" alt="My Euler badge" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
